Hi, I’m Andreas. In this video, I’ll show how I built this Job Application Tracker and how I used an AI coding assistant.
This is a full-stack project with React and TypeScript on the frontend, and Express with JWT authentication on the backend.
First, here is the product demo: users can register, log in, create job applications, and track analytics in real time.
The dashboard includes total applications, interviews, offers, offer rate, monthly trend, and status distribution.
Architecture-wise, the client uses React Query, React Hook Form, Zod, and Recharts. The server uses Express, bcrypt, Zod, and JWT.
I used AI in four phases: scaffolding project structure, implementing features, debugging issues, and improving documentation.
For scaffolding, AI helped generate a clean baseline quickly so I could focus on business logic.
For feature delivery, AI helped draft forms, API integration, and analytics components, which I then reviewed and adapted.
For debugging, AI helped trace registration issues. I improved error handling so users now see clear messages from backend or network failures.
For docs, AI helped produce a recruiter-friendly README and this structured video pack for faster technical review.
The key is ownership: AI suggests options, but I validate builds, verify endpoints, and make final engineering decisions.
My workflow is simple: prompt, inspect, adapt, verify, and ship.
Thanks for watching. If you want, I can also show how I would productionize this with a real database, CI tests, and deployment.